Good! It looks nice!
好啊，看起来不错嘛！
Look carefully. The shadows should be deeper.
仔细看，阴影应该要再深一点
Sometimes the shadows are more important than the lighting.
有时候阴影比光亮更重要
Okay.
好的
How’s it going over here?
这边怎么样了啊？
Great!
很好啊！
Don’t give up!
别放弃啊！
The more you observe things, the better your drawing skills will become.
你观察的事物越多，你的绘画技巧就会越好的
Eh? What’s this?
诶？这是什么？
Hmm… I got it! It’s candy, right?
嗯……我明白了，这是糖果，对吧？
I know you want to eat, but we’re doing sketching practice now.
我知道你想吃东西，但我们现在要做素描练习
Hmm… That’s some extremely suspicious behavior.
嗯…这是一种非常可疑的行为
That pest Fumu is up to something.
那个讨厌的芙姆在搞什么鬼
I bet she’s plotting a way to humiliate you again, Your Majesty.
我打赌她正在密谋要羞辱陛下你呢
That’s it! She’s planning to expose how stupid and thoughtless the country’s ruler is,
就是这样，她打算要揭露这个国家的统治者是多么愚蠢和轻率
and establish a democratic nation of freedom and equality!
然后再建立一个自由平等的民主国家！
Well that sounds splendid!
那听起来太棒了！
Ow...
好痛啊……
As the great dictator, I must completely abolish any kind of anti-government campaign!
作为伟大的独裁者，我必须彻底废除任何形式的反政府运动！
Ah, if it isn’t His Majesty.
啊，是陛下啊
Oh, carry on.
哦，继续
Mayor, you may continue working.
市长，你可以继续工作了
Working? It’s not like that...
工作？不是那样的……
Then what is it?
那这是什么？
Uh, this is, well… I’m thinking of painting that landscape...
啊，这是……好吧……我正在考虑画风景……
Why not use a camera?
为什么不用照相机呢？
There wouldn’t be any meaning in that.
那就没有任何意义了
I think it’s something like this...
我想大概是这样的……
Your Majesty?
是陛下啊
Please don’t look!
请不要看了！
Are you doing things that you can’t have anyone peeking at?
你在做不能让别人偷看的事情吗？
No, nothing like that!
不，不是那样的！
Then what?
那这是什么呢？
I’m just trying to draw that tree…
我只是想画一棵树而已……
You know, sketching.
你知道的，是素描
Sketching?
素描？
What kind of an anti-government activity is sketching?
这是在勾画一场什么样的反政府运行呢？
Anti-government…?
反政府……？
Oh.
啊啦！
Fumu! The main suspect of this treason has appeared!
芙姆，叛国罪的主要嫌疑人出现了！
I’ll arrest you if you make a fool of me!
如果你愚弄我的话，我就逮捕你！
No one’s going to make anything of you, so…
没人会把你怎么样，所以……
Here. If you have some free time, you could draw.
给，如果有空的话，你就可以来画画
How are you going to commit anti-government activities with this?
你用这个怎么从事反政府活动的呢？
Huh?
啊？
Your Majesty, that doesn’t seem to be the case.
陛下，情况似乎并非如此啊
You don’t need to be so suspicious of us.
你们不用这么怀疑我们
Don’t you get it? Everyone’s drawing pictures.
你们不懂吗？每个人都只是在画画而已
Why would you do that?
你，你们为什么要这么做呢？
Ugh!
哎呀，他们正在尝试创造出这个村子所缺少的东西而已！
And that is ART!
这就是艺术！
...Art?
艺术？
To feel a sense of beauty, and to develop an appreciation for beautiful things,
就是去感受一种美，培养对美好事物的欣赏
it’s important to practice drawing and sketching.
练习绘画和素描是很重要的
You hear that? They call it ‘’art’’...
你听到了吗？他们称那是“艺术”
So, where are the weapons?
那么，武器在哪里呢？
Are you really sure about that?
你真的确定和那个有关吗？
Well, there’s going to be an exhibition soon. You’ll understand when you see it!
好吧，很快就会有一个展览，当你们看到的时候就会明白的！
Th-That’s right!
这，这样啊！
Everyone! Our long-awaited art exhibition is now here!
各位，我们期待已久的艺术展现在就来了！
The artworks that you all have been working on so diligently are just wonderful!
大家一直努力创作的作品真是太棒了！
Now let’s begin admiring them right awa-
现在就让我们开始欣赏吧！
I have an announcement for you terrorists. Resistance is futile!
我有个通知要告诉你们这些恐怖分子，抵抗是徒劳的！
Throw down your weapons and disperse!
放下武器，散开！
Oh my...
哦，天哪……
My art career’s a total wash...
我的艺术生涯是彻底完蛋了……
This is an outrage!
这是一种暴行！
Look at what you did to my artwork!
看看你对我们的艺术品都做了些什么！
Why can’t you understand the meaning of art!?
你为什么就是不能理解艺术的意义呢！？
After I worked so hard on it!
这是在我努力之后的成果！
Now it’s all messed up!
现在就是一团糟了！
This village doesn’t even have a little museum where people can enjoy paintings and sculptures!
这个村子甚至没有一个可以让人们欣赏绘画和雕塑的小博物馆！
That’s why we wanted to hold an exhibition here...
所以我们想在这里举办一个展览……
You can’t go doing things like this!
你不能做这种事啊！
But, you know...
但是你要知道……
It would be strange if his Majesty understood art.
如果陛下了解艺术，那就太奇怪了
It’s impossible for Kirby and Dedede.
这对卡比和帝帝帝来说都是不可能的
How about we leave those two be...
不如我们离开那两个人吧……
Is that the lengths you’ll go to make fun of someone?
这就是你们取笑别人的方式吗？
I can make a museum in an instant!
我马上就会建个博物馆的！
Soldiers!
士兵！
How’s that for spacy and luxurious?
这用宽大和豪华来形容怎么样呢？
With this, we can endeavor to improve the people’s artistic culture…
这样，我们就可以努力提高平民的艺术修养了……
The building is awfully big though...
不过，这座楼也太大了
What about inside?
里面呢……
There aren’t any paintings?
就没有任何画吗？
Typical of a box-based government to make a box but not think of the contents.
典型的以盒子为基础的政府制作一个盒子却不考虑里面的内容
It’s something a witless bureaucrat would do.
这是一个愚蠢的官僚会做的事
What’d you say? I’m thinking about the contents now!
什么？我现在正在考虑内容呢！
In that case, I have a suggestion.
那样的话，我有一个建议
Eh?
诶？
What if we all make all the paintings?
所有的画难道不都是大家画的吗？
We’ll choose the best ones in a contest and hang them up here.
我们可以在比赛中选出最好的挂在这里
Sounds good!
听起来不错呢！
So a painting competition?
所以要举行一场绘画比赛吗？
All right! I’ll take first place!
好的，我要拿第一名！
I’ll give out prizes for the ones that make it to the top ten.
我会给那些进入前十名的人颁发奖品的
As expected from you, Your Majesty.
就按您说的，陛下
How generous!
多慷慨啊！
Wait, you’re going to do it for the money?
等等，你是为了钱才这么做的吗？
If we can make money doing art...
如果我们可以通过艺术赚钱……
That would be the greatest!
那会是最棒的！
Okay, I’ll do my best!
好的，我会尽力的！
I’m gonna paint!
我要画画啊！
Wait, everyone!
等等，大家！
We’ve finally fooled them.
我们终于骗了他们
Hanging up THEIR paintings would be a disgrace to the art world!
挂上他们的画将是对艺术界的耻辱啊！
Huh? Famous paintings from around the world?
哈？要来自世界各地的名画？
Not only first-class paintings, but sculptures too!
不仅要一流的画，还要有雕塑呢！
But works of art are expensive.
但是艺术品很贵的
Just one can cost many hundreds of millions of deden. How about a painting demon beast instead…?
仅仅一个就要花费数亿帝元，不如由一只绘画魔兽代替怎么样呢？
Are you trying to make me lose face?!
你想让我丢脸吗？！
You’re always trying to palm off useless demon beasts!
你们总是想赶走那些无用的魔兽！
Well, how about renting?
那么，租赁怎么样呢？
Your Majesty, what do we do?
陛……陛下，我们该怎么办呢？
However, you must return them undamaged within three days.
但是，您必须要在3天之内完好无损地归还
Hurry up!
给我快点！
Listen, everyone! Why are you all painting for money?
大家听听，为什么你们都为了钱而画画呢？
Is there something wrong with that?
有什么问题吗？
Because then it becomes a business!
因为这样就成了做生意了啊！
Is being a business a bad thing?
做生意是件很糟糕的事吗？
Sis, give it up. Isn’t it good that everyone’s painting pictures?
姐姐，放弃吧，每个人都在画画不是很好吗？
But like this...
但是像这样……
Participating applicants, leave your artwork over there and write down your names, addresses, ages and occupations!
申请参加的人，把你们的作品放在那里，然后写下你们的名字、地址、年龄和职业吧！
Commoners, we don’t need your pictures anymore!
平民们，我们不再需要你们的画了！
What?!
诶？！
After I worked so hard on it?!
这可是我努力之后的成果啊！
Since there are submissions from around the world- no, the universe- we’re going to look at those instead!
因为有来自世界各地的参赛作品，不，是来自全宇宙的，我们要去看看他们的艺术！
Fumu, since you know so much about art, you’ll be a judge and pick out the good ones!
芙姆，既然你对艺术了解这么多，那你就当裁判，挑出最好的来！
Huh?
啊？
Now then, unveil the goods.
那么现在，就揭开这些作品的面纱吧
Let the alien art judging begin!
外星艺术评判开始！
This is…!
这个是？
This isn’t a creature from Pupupuland!
这不是噗噗噗之国的生物啊！
Of course not, this was made by aliens from somewhere!
当然不是了，这是某个地方的外星人创作的！
I’ve never seen anything so weird looking!
我从来没见过这么奇怪的东西啊！
This certainly was drawn by a lifeform that may have been different from us!
这可能是由一种与我们截然不同的生命形态所画的！
But it’s so lovely...!
但是她很可爱啊！
This is true art!
这才是真正的艺术啊！
Wha- what!?
什……什么？
Are you out of your mind!?
你疯了吗？
Let’s see the other ones too!
让我们看看其他的吧！
These guys are as ugly as Customer Service.
这些家伙跟客服一样丑
Each and every one of them is grotesque!
他们每个人都很怪诞啊！
This kind of creepy art should be burned!
这种可怕的艺术应该要被烧了！
Don’t say stupid things.
别说傻话了
They're all wonderful…
他们都是很棒的……
This must be greatest treasure in the universe!
这一定是宇宙中最大的宝藏啊！
We should show the villagers too!
我们也应该让村民们看看！
What’re you saying? The commoners would die from sheer terror!
你在说什么呢？平民会因太恐怖而吓死的！
No they wouldn’t! You absolutely have to show this to the public! Right now!
他们不会的，你绝对要向公众展示这一切，现在就来吧！
Oh my, to think that we’ll be able to see paintings by people from a different planet...
咿呀哎呀，我们将能看到来自不同星球人的画了……
I’d call that ground-breaking.
我认为这是突破性的
It’s unbelievable.
真是不可思议
I’m glad I was born in such a good age!
很高兴我能出生在这么好的年代啊！
Anyone who doesn’t see this may regret it for the rest of their lives!
没有看到这些的人可能会后悔一辈子的！
Ladies and gentlemen! An astounding collection of alien art is now on display!
各位，一批令人震惊的外星艺术品正在展出！
I’ve studied each of the works of art,
我研究过每一件艺术品
so I will be your guide in the art museum!
所以我将在艺术博物馆做你们的向导！
We’ll be able to admire the art with Miss Fumu as our guide!
我们将能够欣赏到以芙姆小姐为向导的艺术了！
Oh good!
哦，好耶！
Let’s begin with the sculptures.
让我们从雕塑开始吧
So this is what aliens look like.
那么这就是外星人的样子了
Yes. It’s made of stone, so the arms have broken.
是的，它是由石头制成的，所以胳膊断了
But that only stimulates the imagination!
但是那只会激发想象力！
Doesn’t the body have such beautiful curves?
身体不是有这么美丽的曲线吗？
And this? Is he sitting on a toilet?
这个呢？他坐在马桶上吗？
No, rather… he appears to be thinking about something.
不，而是他似乎在思考着什么
They’re certainly different from us, these aliens.
他们这些外星人，当然是和我们不同的了
In this picture, there is an established perspective.
在这幅画中，有一个既定的立体效果
Oh, perspective?
哦？立体效果？
Please observe! Things that are far away and close are portrayed so realistically,
请注意看，远近的事物被描绘得如此逼真
it’s as if you’re looking at a real building!
就好像你们在看一栋真正的大楼一样！
Well, this is truly amazing.
呀，这真是太棒了
Its impressive.
真是让人印象深刻
The observation and representation of anatomy this painter has done is really excellent.
这位画家对解刨学的观察和表现非常出色
This painting on the ceiling looks like there’s a mythological story behind it.
天花板上的这幅画似乎背后有一个神话故事
Why aren’t there any ones that look like us?
为什么没有像我们一样的人呢？
I don’t understand any of this.
我一点也不明白
Oh, since when did they...
啊，他们什么时候开始……
Now then, as the art techniques develop, you start to see more skill with detailed portrayals,
那么现在，随着艺术技术的发展，你会开始看到更多技巧与细节的描绘
in-depth compositions, and depictions of light and shadow.
深度构图，以及对光和影的描绘
Have a look at this truly dramatic picture.
看看这个真正的戏剧性的画面
When historical events are depicted in paintings, they may have value as a record of what happened!
当历史事件被描绘在画中时，它们可能就有价值来记录发生的事情！
And from here we leave the events of mythology and history,
从这里我们就要离开神话和历史事件了
and move on to paintings with a natural scenery full of light that is all around us!
然后继续我们周围充满阳光的自然风景画了！
My, how lovely!
哇，多么漂亮的东西啊！
Not as lovely as you...
不如你漂亮的……
Many of the artworks decorating these walls here portray landscapes and people,
许多装饰这些墙壁的艺术品描绘了人和风景
but a revolution in art style is present.
但是一场艺术风格的革命已经到来了
Look! Isn’t the depiction of light and shadow splendid when painted with many dots of color?
看！当画了许多点的颜色时，光和影的描绘不就很精彩吗？
They tried to make a beautiful impression itself into a painting,
他们试图给自己留下美丽的印象
so I call it Impressionism!
所以称之为“印象派”！
How about some Kawasaki special sandwiches while you appreciate the art?
在欣赏艺术的同时，要不要来点川崎特制三明治呢？
Anyone is welcome to hear my prediction of their artistic taste!
欢迎大家来听我对他们艺术的品味的预测吧！
I wonder if I have any?
我想知道我有没有品味呢？
That’s too funny!
那太有趣了！
What is this stuff?
这是什么东西啊？
These are total crap!
这些绝对是劣质品啊！
Ah, I think these are attempts at breaking away from the usual way of seeing things.
啊，我想这些都是试图打破通常的看待事物的方式
But bad is still bad!
但是不好就是不好啊！
Yay, those look funny!
哇，那些看起来真有趣啊！
These are attempts to overturn the accepted way of making art,
这些都是试图推翻公认的艺术创作方式
and give a new meaning to advertising and the everyday life we’re used to.
赋予了广告和我们习惯的日常生活新的意义
What is this?
这个是什么啊？
That’s confusing..
太让人困惑了……
But it looks fun!
但看起来很有趣啊！
Instead of drawing anything specific, these are attempts to understand what art itself really is.
这些都是试图理解艺术本身是什么，而不是画任何具体的东西
I see, looking at it, that might be true-
我明白了，看上去，这可能是真的……
What’s there to admire?! Even I could made this kind of art!
有什么值得钦佩的？！就连我都能创作出这种艺术来的！
Your Majesty, when did you...
陛下，你什么时候创作了啊？
Now, you’ll see MY art!
现在，你们会看到我的艺术品的！
This is the special exhibition room for my art!
这是我的艺术特别展览室！
This is me! I’m the big star, therefore I’m drawn big and cute right in the middle.
这就是我，我是大明星，所以我在中间被画得又大又可爱
Instead of bothering with perspective, I drew it while wearing bifocals.
我没有费心透视，而是戴着双光眼镜画的
Here’s my castle, and a pooping Escargon.
这里是我的城堡，还有一坨艾斯卡卢工拉的屎💩
Here’s the mayor and his sheep.
这是市长和他的羊
This is Kirby, who’s pooping after eating too much. Realism at its finest!
这是卡比，他吃了太多的屎💩了，是最好的现实主义者
I can’t determine if it’s art or not...
我不知道这是不是艺术……
It’s too ridiculous...
太荒谬了……
I’m gonna die laughing…
我会笑死的……
Are you laughing at my art!?
你们是在嘲笑我的艺术吗？
Ah, Your Majesty...
啊，陛下……
Anyone laughing gets a 10,000 year sentence with torture. and that's me showing mercy!
任何嘲笑我的人都要被判10000年徒刑的，这已经是我的仁慈了！
Send me a real artist!
给我一个真正的艺术家吧！
We’re all out of artists, but I can give you a demon beast...
我们都是没有艺术家的，但我可以给你一个魔兽……
Anything that can draw pictures is fine!
任何会画画的家伙都可以！
What’s that guy?
那家伙是什么啊？
The Drawing Demon Beast, Paint Roller.
这是绘画魔兽，画家罗勒
He will paint a picture of anything you command.
他可以把你所吩咐的一切都描绘出来
Alright, change all of the alien art into my style right away!
好，把所有的外星艺术品都换成我的风格吧！
Ahh, stop it!
啊，不要啊！
Capture him!
抓住他！
I can forgive a little creative license!
我可以免除一些创意性的许可！
If the stuff we borrowed looks like this, we’ll be charged for damaging them!
如果我们借来的东西看起来像这样，我们会因为损坏它们而被起诉的！
You fool! This is shameless!  Is this some big joke, you dolt?
你这个傻瓜，你这也太无耻了！这是闹着玩的吗，你是个笨蛋吗？
Since your only crime was painting me, I’ll forgive you in exchange for painting my beautiful portrait!
既然你唯一的罪过就是画我，那我就原谅你画我美丽的肖像吧！
Oh, what a disaster...
啊，真是一场灾难啊……
It’s ruined!
全毁了啊！
We have to fix it somehow...
我们必须设法解决它……
It’s alive! The painting came to life!
它是活的，这幅画是活的！
Speaking of that, sis, that guy is painting Dedede right now!
说到这个，姐姐，那家伙现在正在画帝帝帝呢！
That means...!
那就是说……
Is it ready?
完成了吗？
I’m ready.
我完成了
Wha-what!?
什……什么！？
I’m the ruler!
我是统治者！
Wha!?
什么！？
Your Majesty, over here!
陛下，过来！
Dedede!
帝帝帝！
My own portrait turned on me!
我自己的画像攻击了我！
That’s because you used a demon beast!
那是因为你用了魔兽啊！
It’s going after Kirby!
它在追卡比啊！
The true enemy is Paint Roller!
真正的敌人是画家罗勒！
Paint…?
画家？
Its paintings become real! If it paints something dangerous...
它的画会变成现实，如果画出一些危险的东西的话……
Oh no!
哦，不！
Kirby, inhale!
卡比，吸入！
Yes, it’s Paint Kirby!
太好了，是画家卡比！
This is bad! Everyone, run!
这下糟了，大家快跑！
Kirby!
卡比！
You did it!
你成功了！
We’re going to have to pay for the damages again...
我们将不得不再次赔偿损失了……
Look! Now this is art!
看，这就是艺术啊！
Escargon.
艾斯卡卢工！
Huh?
啊？
What are you building?
你在制造什么呢？
It’s a secret! Just go away, geez!
这是一个秘密，快走开啦！
What are you so angry about!?
你为什么这么生气呢！？
Isn’t it obvious!? It’s his Majesty!
这不很明显吗？是陛下呀！
Even though I hate working, he’s always telling me to ‘’do this, do that’"!
就算我讨厌工作，他也总是吩咐我干这个干那个的！
Seriously, he really pushes people too hard!
说真的，他真的把人逼得太紧了！
Maybe ‘cause you work at a snail’s pace?
也许是因为你如同一只蜗牛般的工作速度吧？
Shut up! Even for you and Kirby, the next one should be huge!
闭嘴，即使是对于芙姆你们和卡比来说，下一集也应该是一个巨大的工作！